ALBERT SZULC

Software developer focused on developing **clean**, **well-structured** and **extensible software**. Believing in the power of **collaboration**, I excel in team environments that leverage collective expertise. With a solid knowledge of **server-side** web development, I am enthusiastic about applying and advancing these skills in my future projects, while adhering to **modern standards** and **best practices**.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Ö 05.2022 - 08.2024

Adgency

Pielefeld, Germany

- Played a key role in deciding the architecture of a **full-stack** web application with a three-tier structure, resulting in an easily maintainable and extensible system.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather requirements; initiated **structured documentation** of those decisions, ensuring clear communication and better teamwork.
- Developed **50+ REST** endpoints in **Go** using controller-service-repository pattern, ensuring easily modifiable and maintainable code.
- Created **unit** and **integration tests** concurrently with production code for backend services, achieving **80%+ test coverage** and significantly improving system reliability.
- Designed (ERP Diagram) and implemented a relational database with 30+ tables PostgreSQL
- Reduced code duplication by creating a separate **Go module** for code used by all projects in the company.
- Prepared **Docker** containers for development, test and production environments, creating a unified setup across all developers and reducing environment configuration issues.
- Managed **Git** repositories and served as the go-to person for resolving complex merge conflicts, ensuring smooth collaboration.
- Introduced stacked diffs, allowing developers to work on changes independently of PR merges into the main branch, resulting in **faster development cycles**.
- Suggested and implemented **CI pipeline** to automate execution of tests before merging, resulting in significantly fewer bugs in the production code **Github Actions**
- Implemented API plugin to standardize and simplify HTTP requests to the backend **TypeScript**, **Vue.is**
- Set up database migration tool Liquibase

Programming Intern

1 08.2021 - 09.2021

Capgemini

Poznań, Poland

- Enhanced **Git** proficiency by working on a large scale project.
- Completed minor tasks in an agile team under experienced developers' supervision.



EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Software Design & Engineering

🗖 09.2024 - Present

FH Campus Wien

Program Focus: Gaining comprehensive expertise in all critical stages of the data development process, from project planning to maintenance.

Most relevant courses (taken up to now): Advanced Software Development, Software Architectures, Cloud Computing, Requirements Engineering

B.Eng. in Computer Science

10.2018 - 02.2022

Poznań University of Technology

Bachelor Thesis: Developed a front-end web application using React that allows users to track the real-time position of their vehicles on an interactive map.

Most relevant courses: Algorithms and Data Structures, Operating Systems, Object Oriented Programming, Database Systems, Computer Networks, Software Engineering, Advanced Internet Applications, Cloud Computing, Cryptography.

CONTACT INFO

in linkedin.com/in/a-szulc

☑ szulcalbert@gmail.com

SKILLS

BACKEND:

• Go • Java • Spring

DATABASE:

- SQL Relational Databases
- Data Modeling PostgreSQL

OPERATING SYSTEMS:

• Linux

CONTAINERIZATION:

• Docker • Kubernetes

TESTING:

• Unit • Integration

MISCELLANEOUS:

• Git • REST

FRONTEND:

- HTML CSS JavaScript
- TypeScript Vue.js
- Bootstrap

LANGUAGES

• English: Fluent (C1)

• German: Fluent (C1)

• Polish: Native speaker

SIDE PROJECTS

♀ github.com/albiosz

 honeycombs (REST, Java, Spring, Docker, JWT, JUnit)

• go-rest (REST, Go)

AWARDS

• Scholarship for the top 10% of students at the Faculty of Computer Science | Poznan University of Technology

STUDENT EXCHANGE

- Bielefeld University
- 03.2021 02.2022